<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Docker on Jarek Przygódzki&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://jarek-przygodzki.github.io/tags/docker/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Docker on Jarek Przygódzki&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://jarek-przygodzki.github.io/tags/docker/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Why is my Docker image so large?</title>
      <link>https://jarek-przygodzki.github.io/post/why-is-my-docker-image-so-large/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarek-przygodzki.github.io/post/why-is-my-docker-image-so-large/</guid>
      <description>Keeping Docker images as small as possible has a lot of practical benefits. But even when following best practices
 use stripped-down base image utilize multi-stage builds don&amp;rsquo;t install what you don&amp;rsquo;t need optimize build context minimize number of layers  some images end up being larger than they have to be inadvertently including files that are not necessary .
How to troubleshoot issues with image size? Image filesystem changes are tracked in layers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A curious case of slow Docker image builds</title>
      <link>https://jarek-przygodzki.github.io/post/a-curious-case-of-slow-docker-image-builds/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarek-przygodzki.github.io/post/a-curious-case-of-slow-docker-image-builds/</guid>
      <description>Investigating slow Docker image builds A rather short but hopefully interesting troubleshooting story that happened recently.
Lately, I was investigating a case of slow Docker image builds on CI server (Oracle Linux 7.5 with Docker devicemapper storage driver in direct-lvm mode). Each operation which altered layers (ADD, COPY, RUN) took up to 20 seconds - the larger the image, the longer.
A typical way of dealing with with apparently stuck program is collecting thread stack traces.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generating JVM memory dumps from JRE</title>
      <link>https://jarek-przygodzki.github.io/post/generating-jvm-memory-dumps-from-jre/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarek-przygodzki.github.io/post/generating-jvm-memory-dumps-from-jre/</guid>
      <description>Generating JVM memory dumps from JRE on Linux/Windows/OSX Generating a JVM heap memory dump with JDK is straightforward as almost every Java developer knows about jmap and jcmd tools that come with the JDK. But what about JRE?
Some people think you need JDK, or at least part of it, but that&amp;rsquo;s not true. The answer lies in jattach, a tool to send commands to JVM via Dynamic Attach mechanism created by JVM hacker Andrei Pangin (@AndreiPangin).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Install Ca Certificate for Docker Registry on Local Boot2docker Vm</title>
      <link>https://jarek-przygodzki.github.io/post/install-ca-certificate-for-docker-registry-on-local-boot2docker-vm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarek-przygodzki.github.io/post/install-ca-certificate-for-docker-registry-on-local-boot2docker-vm/</guid>
      <description>Annoyingly often internal Docker registries are secured with certificates signed by company&amp;rsquo;s own PKI or enterprise IT does a MitM to replace all HTTPS certs.
Commonly, company&amp;rsquo;s root CA certificate is installed by IT on developers machines and servers, but not on VMs run by developers on their own machines. When using Docker with local VMs like boot2docker, do we need to install the company root CA certificate on the VM to avoid x509: certificate signed by unknown authority errors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publishing a port from a running Docker container</title>
      <link>https://jarek-przygodzki.github.io/post/publishing-a-port-from-a-running-docker-container/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarek-przygodzki.github.io/post/publishing-a-port-from-a-running-docker-container/</guid>
      <description>It’s not obvious, but it’s possible to publish an additional port from a running Docker container.
Note: Assuming container is attached to user-defined bridge network or default bridge network. Publishing ports doesn’t make sense with MacVLAN or IPVLAN since then every container has a uniquely routable IP address and can offer service on any port.
What can we do to make container port externally accessible? One possibile solution is to exploit the fact that communication between containers inside the same bridge network is switched at layer 2 and they can communiate with each other without any restrictions (unless ICC is disabled, that is).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monitorowanie i przechwytywanie ruchu sieciowego kontenerów Dockera</title>
      <link>https://jarek-przygodzki.github.io/post/monitorowanie-i-przechwytywanie-ruchu-sieciowego-kontenerow-docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarek-przygodzki.github.io/post/monitorowanie-i-przechwytywanie-ruchu-sieciowego-kontenerow-docker/</guid>
      <description>Ten wpis to krótki tutorial jak przechwycić ruch sieciowych z wybranych kontenerów Dockera, np. usług uruchomionych w ramach klastra Docker Swarm.
Na początek minimum teorii. Docker używa przestrzeni nazw w celu zapewnienia izolacji procesów. Przestrzenie nazw (których od jądra 4.10 jest 7 rodzajów) są cechą jądra systemu Linux, która pozwala na izolację i wirtualizację zasobów systemowych. Funkcja przestrzeni nazw jest taka sama dla każdego typu: każdy proces jest powiązany z przestrzenią nazw danego rodzaju i może wykorzystywać zasoby powiązane z tą przestrzenią, oraz, w stosownych przypadkach, przestrzeniami nazw potomków.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running Linux graphical applications in Docker on Windows with Cygwin/X</title>
      <link>https://jarek-przygodzki.github.io/post/running-linux-graphical-applications-in-docker-on-windows-with-cygwinx/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarek-przygodzki.github.io/post/running-linux-graphical-applications-in-docker-on-windows-with-cygwinx/</guid>
      <description>Install Babun Cygwin is a great tool, but not the easiest to install. Babun consists of a pre-configured Cygwin that does not interfere with existing Cygwin installation.
Download the dist file from http://babun.github.io, unzip it and run the install.bat script. After a few minutes the application will be installed to the %USERPROFILE%\.babun directory. You can use the /target (or /t) option to install babun to a custom directory.
Install Cygwin/X Run pact from babun shell (pact is a babun package manager )</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JVM in Docker and PTRACE_ATTACH</title>
      <link>https://jarek-przygodzki.github.io/post/jvm-in-docker-and-ptrace_attach/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jarek-przygodzki.github.io/post/jvm-in-docker-and-ptrace_attach/</guid>
      <description>Docker nowadays (since 1.10, the original pull request is here docker/docker/#17989) adds some security to running containers by wrapping them in both AppArmor (or presumably SELinux on RedHat systems) and seccomp eBPF based syscall filters (here’s a nice article about it). And ptrace is disabled in the default seccomp profile.
$ docker run alpine sh -c &#39;apk add -U strace &amp;amp;&amp;amp; strace echo&#39; fetch http://dl-cdn.alpinelinux.org/alpine/v3.4/main/x86_64/APKINDEX.tar.gz fetch http://dl-cdn.alpinelinux.org/alpine/v3.4/community/x86_64/APKINDEX.tar.gz (1/1) Installing strace (4.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>